The future
a dark, desolate world.
A world of war.
Suffering.
Loss on both sides.
Mutants and the humans who
dared to help them.
Fighting an enemy
we cannot defeat.
Are we destined on this path?
Destined to destroy ourselves
like so many species before us?
Or can we evolve fast enough
to change ourselves?
Change our fate?
Is the future truly set?
They're here.
Time's up. Sentinels.
Sunspot.
Let's go.
Run.
Blink
No.
Too late assholes...
So few of us left.
Professor.
I found them.
Bobby.
Hey kid.
Professor, you made it.
Whenever the sentinels attack
warpath spots them...
and I send bishop back to warn us
of the attack before it happens.
Blink scouts the next site and...
well, then we leave before
they ever know we were there.
Because we never were.
What do you mean
you were never there?
She projects bishop back in time a few days
to warn the others of the coming attack.
Then she sends
bishop back in time.
No, just his consciousness into
his younger self his younger body.
This might just work Charles.
What might work?
The sentinel program was originally
conceived by doctor Bolivar Trask.
In the early 70's he was one of the
world's leading weapons designers.
But covert he had begun
experimenting on mutants...
using their gifts to
fuel his own research.
There was one mutant who had
discovered what he was doing.
A mutant with the ability to
transform herself into anyone.
Mystique.
I knew her as Raven.
We met when we were children,
grew up together.
She was like a sister to me.
I tried to help her but only
succeeded in driving her away.
She hunted Trask
across the world...
and at the Paris peace accords in 1973
after the Vietnam war she found Trask
and killed him.
It was the first time she killed.
It wasn't her last.
But killing Trask did not
have the outcome she expected.
It only persuaded the government
to believe in his program.
They captured her that day.
Tortured her.
Experimented on her.
In her DNA they discovered the secrets
to her powers of transformation.
It gave them the key
they needed to create...
weapons that could adapt
to any mutant power...
and the result is the
machines that have
destroyed so many of our
kind were created...
and it all started
that day in 1973.
The day she first killed the
day she truly became Mystique.
You wanna go back there?
If I can get to her,
stop the assassination,
keep her out of their hands...
then we can stop the
sentinels from ever being born
and end this war
before it ever begins.
I can send someone
back a couple of weeks...
maybe a month but you're
talking about going back decades.
You have the most powerful
brain in the world... Professor
but the mind can only stretch
so far before it snaps
it would rip you apart I'm sorry
no one could survive that trip.
What if someone's mind
has a way of snapping back?
What if someone could heal
as fast as they rip apart?
Ok spread out.
Get in position.
So I wake up in my younger
body, God knows where, then what?
You'll need to go to
my house and find me.
Convince me of all of this.
Won't you just be
able to read my mind?
I didn't have my powers in 1973.
Logan, you're going to have to do for
me what I once did for you.
Lead me, guide me.
I was a very
different man then.
You'll have to be patient with me.
Patience isn't my strongest suit.
You'll need me as well.
What?
After Mystique left Charles she came
with me and I set her on a dangerous path.
A darker path.
It's going to take the
two of us side by side.
At a time when we
couldn't be further apart.
Great.
So where do I find you?
Well, it's complicated.
Basically your body will go to sleep,
while your mind travels back in time.
As long as you're back there past
and present will continue to coexist.
But once you wake up...
whatever you've done will
take hold and become history.
And for the rest of us it'll be
the only history that we know.
It'll be like the last
50 years never happened.
In this world, this war.
The only person who
will remember it is you.
Alright Logan I need you to clear your
head and to stay as calm as possible.
What, what do you mean?
If your mind gets rocky it'll
be harder for me to hold you.
You could start to slip
between past and future.
What if I need to
get a little rocky.
Think peaceful thoughts.
Peaceful thoughts.
Do you have any good news?
Well, you don't really age so
you'll pretty much look the same.
You won't have much
time in the past.
Sentinels will find us.
They always do.
And this time we won't be able
to run, we'll have no escape.
This is our last chance.
Do you really think
this will work?
I have faith in him.
It's not him I'm worried
about, it us, we were young.
We didn't know any better.
We will now.
As we always do.
This might sting a little.
Holy shit.
What?
Hey! What's going on?
Get dressed.
Hey... I don't know what's going on.
What's going on is that
you're supposed to be...
guarding the boss' daughter,
not screwing her.
I didn't sleep with her.
- No?
- No.
I mean yes, I slept
with her many times but...
Jimmy!
That wasn't me, that was the old me,
I just got here like 20 seconds ago.
Really, yeah.
Well then what happened
to your clothes?
Would you believe me if I told you
I was sent here from the future?
What?
Get out of here sweetheart, yeah!
We're gonna take
care of this comedian.
No you're not.
You're gonna give me the
keys to your car and some...
money for gas or you're gonna
wake up in the hospital.
Trust me, I know how
these things play out.
Oh,
because you're from the future.
No, because of these.
What the hell!
Goddammit!
Peaceful thoughts.
We are reviewing all of
our defense expenditures...
and all the black
books are being opened.
We can't support a weapon
that targets our own citizens.
If these mutants as you
described are already living...
among us then they are
living here peacefully.
We haven't had an
incident in over 10 years.
After what happened in Cuba,
it was never confirmed.
We have real enemies out there,
the Russians, the Chinese.
We are talking about a tenth of a
tenth of a tenth of our population.
Allow me to read
something to you.
Please.
This was acquired by
our friends at the CIA.
It's a dissertation written by a
mutant at Oxford university and I quote...
to Homo-Neanderthals,
his mutant cousin Homosapiens
which is us.
Was an aberration, the arrival of the
mutated human species, Homosapiens...
was followed by the immediate
extinction of their less evolved kind.
Well, now we are the Neanderthal.
Speak for yourself Dr. Trask.
You know, when you sent
those soldiers to Vietnam...
without the weapons, they
needed to win the war.
You underestimated your enemy.
You do that with this
enemy, it won't be some...
border skirmish halfway
around the world.
This time the war will be for our
streets, our cities, our homes
and by the time you see the
need for my program, it'll be...
too late and you will have
lost two wars in one lifetime.
We're sorry Dr. Trask.
But your sentinel program,
it ain't gonna fly.
Can I help you Colonel?
Just here to give our
boys a proper send off.
Sorry Sir! But we have orders.
This is a Quarantined Area.
Stand aside Soldier!
That's an order.
Attention!
At ease.
What is all this?
Lab reports, blood tests.
Some getting packed
up and shipped back.
Where is it going?
Same place they are.
Trask Industries.
Let's go gentlemen.
Taking you outta this shit show.
Shipping home?
Not just yet.
What are you doing with those?
It's gonna make the
ride a little smoother.
We're transferring you to a
private facility where we can...
run a few more tests.
Your men are not military.
Private outfit.
We're authorized
to remand these men.
These troops are going home.
Well, colonel, I don't think you
have jurisdiction in this matter.
I'm afraid I do son.
I'm sorry who are you?
The question is major...
who are you?
Raven.
That's not my name.
I had him.
I know.
Let's move out, come on let's go.
Where's Eric? I'm on my own now.
Let's go move it.
Hold that plane.
Wouldn't wanna leave these boys
in this godforsaken country.
You're not coming
with us are you?
My war's not over,
the enemy is still out there.
Where'd they go?
The four privates,
where'd they go?
They were headed
towards the Tarmac.
Can I help you?
Uh yeah,
what happened to the school?
School's been shut for years.
Are you a parent?
Sure as hell hope not.
Who are you?
I'm Hank, Hank McCoy,
I look after the house now.
You're Beast?
Look at you, well,
I guess you're a late bloomer.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm gonna have to
ask you to leave.
So where's the Professor?
There's no Professor here.
You're pretty strong
for a scrawny kid.
Come on, sure there's
not a Beast in there.
Come on! Beast.
There's no one here
Come on! Beastie.
I said this school is closed,
you need to leave.
Not until I see the Professor.
There's no Professor here,
I told you that.
Look kid
you and I are gonna
be good friends.
You just don't know it yet.
Professor!
Hank, what's going on here?
Please don't call me that.
You know this guy.
Yeah, he looks slightly familiar,
get off the bloody chandelier. Hank!
You can walk.
You're a perceptive one.
I thought Erik...
Which was likely that you managed
to miss our sign on the way in,
this is a private property my friend,
I'm gonna ask him to ask you to leave.
Well, I'm afraid I
can't do that because...
because I was sent here for you.
Well, tell whoever it was
that sent you that I'm busy.
This is gonna be a little tricky
because the person who sent me was you.
What!
About 50 years from now.
50 years from now like in
the future 50 years from now?
Yeah.
I sent you from the future.
Piss off!
If you had your powers you would
know I was telling the truth.
How do you know
I don't have my..
Who are you?
I told you.
Are you CIA?
No.
You were watching me.
I know you Charles.
We've been friends for years.
I know your powers
came when you were 9.
I know you thought you
were going crazy when
it started, all the
voices in your head.
And it wasn't until you
were 12 that you realized
that all the voices were
in everyone else's head
do you want me to go on?
I never told anyone that.
Not yet no but, you will.
Alright you've piqued my
interest, what do you want?
We have to stop Raven.
I need your help.
We need your help.
Think I'd like to wake up now.
What does she have
to do with this?
So you're saying that they took Raven's
power and what, they weaponized it.
Yup.
She is unique.
Yes she is.
In the beginning the sentinels
were just targeting mutants.
Then they began to identify
the genetics in non-mutants.
Who'd eventually have mutant
children or grandchildren.
Many of the humans tried to
help us, it was a slaughter.
Leaving only the worst
of humanity in charge.
I've been in a lot of wars.
I've never seen
anything like this.
And it all starts with her.
Let's just say that for
the sake of, sake that...
I choose to believe you,
that I choose to help you...
Raven won't listen to me.
No her heart and soul
belongs to someone else now.
I know.
That's why we're
gonna need Magneto too.
Eric, you do know where he is?
Yeah.
He's where he belongs.
So that's it,
you're just gonna walk out.
Oh top marks, like I said,
you are perceptive.
The Professor I know would never turn
his back on someone who lost their path
especially someone he loved.
You know,
I think I do remember you now.
Yeah, we came to you a long
time ago seeking your help.
And I'm gonna say to you
what you said to us then.
Fuck off!
Listen to me you little shit!
I've come a long way, and I watched a
lot of people die, good people, friends.
If you're gonna wallow in
self-pity and do nothing...
then you're gonna watch the
same thing, you understand?
We all have to die some time.
Told you there was
no Professor here.
What the hell happened to him?
He lost everything.
Eric, Raven, his legs.
We built the school,
the labs, this whole place.
Then just after the first semester
the war in Vietnam got worse.
Many of the teachers and all
the students were drafted.
It really broke him.
He retreated into himself.
I wanted to help do something so I
designed a serum to treat his spine.
Derived from the same formula
that helps me control my mutation.
I take just enough to keep myself
balanced but he takes too much.
I tried easing him back but
he just couldn't bear the pain.
The voices, the treatment gives him
his legs but it's not enough.
He's just lost too much.
You're not scared of me?
I always believed I couldn't
be the only one in the world.
Charles Xavier.
Raven.
You're hungry and alone?
Take whatever you want, we've got
lots of food, you don't have to steal.
In fact you never
have to steal again
and that's a promise.
I'll help you get her.
But not for any of your
future shots but for her.
Fair enough.
Tell you this, you don't know Eric,
that man is a monster, a murderer.
You think you can convince
Raven to change, to come home.
Splendid!
But what makes you
think you can change him?
Because you and Eric sent
me back here together.
The room they're holding him
in was built during the...
2nd World War when there
was a shortage of steel.
So the foundation is pure
concrete and sand, no metal.
And he's being held a
100 floors beneath the
most heavily guarded
building on the planet.
Why is he in there?
What, he forgot to mention?
Uh JFK.
He killed.
What else would explain the bullet
miraculously curving through the air.
Eric's always had
a way with guns.
You're sure you want
to carry on with this?
Well, this is your plan not mine.
We don't have any resources
to get us in, or out.
It's just me and Hank.
I know a guy.
Yeah, he'd be a young man now
grew up outside of DC.
He could get into anywhere, just don't
know how the hell we're gonna find him.
With Cerebro out of the question.
We have a phone book.
I thought you'd be getting
ready for your trip Sir.
I just came to
grab a couple files.
Is that a new scarf, it's nice.
Thank you.
Dr. Trask.
One second.
We added some names
to the Paris meeting.
Thank you.
Is something wrong Sir?
No, it's nothing.
Would you mind taping up my
itinerary? I don't wanna miss anything.
Stop! Don't get used to it.
What has he done now?
I'll just write you a
check for whatever he took.
We just need talk to him.
Peter, the cops are here, again.
I didn't do anything.
I've been here all day.
Just relax Peter, we're not cops.
Course you're not cops, if you were
cops you wouldn't drive a rental car.
How'd you know we
got a rental car?
I checked your registration when
you were walking through the door.
I also had some time to kill so I
went through your rental agreements.
Saw you were from out of town,
are you FBI?
No, you're not cops, hey
what's up with this gypsy place?
That's an old card.
Well he's fascinating.
He's a pain in the ass.
What, a teleporter?
No, he's just fast but when
I knew him he wasn't so young.
Young, you're just old.
So you're not afraid
to show your powers?
Powers!, what powers?,
what are you talking about?
Did you see something
strange here?
Nothing anybody would
believe you if you told them.
So who are you and
what do you want?
We need your help, Peter.
With what?
Break into a highly secured
facility and get someone out.
Prison break.
That's illegal you know.
Well, only if you get caught.
So what's in it for me?
You, the kleptomaniac,
get to break into the Pentagon.
How do I know I can trust you?
Because we're just like you.
Show him.
It's cool, just disgusting.
Built in 1943 the Pentagon is the
world's largest office building housing.
More than 25000 military and police
stretched over 6 million square feet.
Where is the bathroom?
Yeah, we're getting broadcast
signal down here, what's going on?
Damn it, call maintenance,
get him down here.
In 3 seconds those doors are going to open
and 20 guards will be here to shoot us.
I know,
that's what I'm waiting for.
What are you doing?
I'm holding your neck so
you won't get whiplash.
What?
Whip... lash.
Don't move!
You're good, it'll pass.
It happens with everyone.
Must have done
something pretty serious.
What'd you do?
Why'd they have you in there?
For killing the President.
The only thing I'm guilty of
is fighting for people like us.
You take karate,
you're a karate man?
I don't know karate,
but I know crazy.
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and
girls this is a code red situation.
We are evacuating the
entire floor so that we...
my uh associate and I can
uh secure the prisoner.
Who are you?
We are special operations CB,
FE, CIE.
Look, perhaps you didn't hear
me at first but it's imperative
that, you understand we're in
complete lock-down situation.
We have to get to the 3rd floor.
Oh I'm sorry were you finished.
They told me you control metal.
They?
You know, my mom once knew
a guy who could do that.
Sorry, I'm just not
very good with violence.
Charles.
Good to see you too old friend...
and walking.
No thanks to you.
You're the last person in the
world I expected to see today.
Believe me.
I wouldn't be here
if I didn't have to.
If we get you out of here
we do it my way, no killing.
No helmet.
I couldn't disobey
you even if I wanted.
I'm never getting inside
of that head again.
I need your word, Eric.
Nobody move.
Hold it right there.
Charles.
Don't move.
Hands up or we will shoot.
Freeze them Charles.
I can't.
No.
Thanks kid.
Peter thank you very very much.
You take care.
Why are you going to Paris?
Imagine if they were metal.
Do me a favor and
return it for me.
And Peter.
Take it slow.
Where did they dig you up?
You're gonna find this hard
to believe but uh, you sent me.
You and Charles, from the future.
How did you lose them
the treatment for my
spine fixed my DNA.
You sacrificed your
power so you could walk.
I sacrificed my power
so that I could sl..
What do you know about it?
I lost my fair share.
Hah...
Dry your eyes. Eric!
Doesn't justify what you've done.
You have no idea what I've done.
I know that you took the
things that mean most to me.
Well maybe you should have
fought harder for them.
Do you want to fight? Eric. I
will give you a fight. Sit down...
let him come.
You abandoned me.
You took her away
and you abandoned me.
Angel, Azazel, Emma, Banshee...
our mutant brothers
and sisters... all dead,
captured, experimented on,
butchered.
Eric.
Where were you Charles?
We were supposed to protect them.
Where were you when your
own people needed you.
Hiding.
You and Hank.
Pretending you were
something you're not.
Eric.
You abandoned us all.
So you were always an asshole.
I take it we're best
buddies in the future.
I spent a lot of years
trying to bring you down, bub.
How's that work out for you?
You're like me.
You're a survivor.
Wanna pick all that shit up?
I'm sorry..
No. It was my fault.
Fancy a game
been a while.
I'm not in the mood
for games thank you.
Haven't had a real
sip in 10 years.
I didn't kill the President.
The bullet curved Eric.
Because I was trying to save him.
They took me out before I could.
Why would you try and save him?
Because he was one of us.
You must think me so foolish.
We always said they
would come after us.
I never imagined they would
use Raven's DNA to do it.
When did you last see her?
The day I left for Dallas.
And how was she?
Strong, driven, loyal.
How, how was she?
She was...
I could see why she
had so much talent?
You should be proud
of her Charles.
She's out there
fighting for our cause.
Your cause?
The girl I raise,
she was not capable of killing.
You didn't raise her,
you grew up with her.
She couldn't stay a little girl
forever that's why she left.
She left because you
got inside her head.
That's not my power.
She made a choice.
But now we know where that
choice leads, don't we?
She's going to murder
Trask, they're going to...
capture her, and then they're
going to wipe us out.
Not if we get to her first.
Not if we change
history tomorrow.
I'm sorry Charles.
For what happened, I truly am.
It's been a while since I played.
I'll go easy on you.
Might finally get a fair fight.
You have the first move.
The diplomats all around the world are
arriving here today, at the hotel royale.
A historic day as the
official ending of the...
United States' fierce
involvement in Vietnam.
There's the South
vietnamese foreign minister
with other South
vietnamese dignitaries.
The summit doesn't
begin for another hour.
The hotel has arranged a private
room upstairs for your special guest.
There will be plenty of time.
Good afternoon everyone,
hello, thank you for coming.
Congratulations on
winning this war.
Now I know you all have
hands to shake and photos
to take downstairs so I
will get right to the point.
There is a new enemy out there.
An enemy that will render
your arsenals useless,
your armies powerless and
your nations defenseless.
You'll need a new
weapon for this war.
I call them Sentinels.
Named after the ancient guardians
that stood at the gates of the Citadel.
They have the aeronautic
capabilities of a harrier jet,
armed with guns that can
fire off more than 2000
rounds per minute with
thermo-ceramic ammunition.
But size, power, speed, you can
find that at Lockheed or Boeing.
No, what makes the sentinels so special
is the ability to target the Mutant-X gene.
A genetic guidance system that can
lock onto a mark half a mile away
and won't trigger unless it
has identified the target.
With this weapon there'll be
no human collateral damage.
If I turn it on the system
couldn't even activate in here
unless there's a mutant.
There has to be
some kind of mistake.
My machines don't make mistakes.
What are you?
I assure you.
No don't shoot it.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Raven.
Charles.
We've come for you,
Eric and I, together.
I never thought I
could see you again.
I'm going to keep you safe I'm
going to keep you out of their hands.
Eric.
Eric, what are you doing?
Securing our future.
Forgive me Mystique, as long as
you're out there we'll never be safe.
Eric.
Use your powers Charles,
stop him.
He can't.
He's slipping he's slipping back.
Stryker!
Restrain him.
No.
Eric.
Where am I?
How the hell did I get here?
What, you came to us?
Who are you?
Charles.
Charles Xavier.
I don't know you.
The hell is that.
Whoa whoa, I can deal with
this, just go, stop Eric.
I'm sorry.
You're Logan, that's
Hank McCoy, I'm Charles.
Xavier, you spent the last
couple of days with us.
You're on acid.
Somebody gave you
really bad acid.
Yeah?
Just hold on tight we'll
get through this together.
Oh God, Kitty.
She's wounded pretty bad.
I got him back.
Professor.
What happened to you?
I just saw someone who's going
to bring me a lot of pain someday.
Where's Raven?
Gone.
Why?
We have to get out of here.
Yesterday the Paris
peace summit was rocked...
by the appearance of
unidentified assailants.
The likes of which the
world has never seen.
Mass hysteria has gripped
the nation as people ask:
Where do they come
from, will they be back?
And most importantly
are they friend or foe?
What the hell are
we dealing with here.
Off the record.
2 days ago this man
Eric Lehnsherr
escaped from a maximum
prison inside the Pentagon.
We believe that this woman is a
former associate of Lehnsherr's.
They were together in Cuba at
the day of the crisis in '62.
He was also linked to
the Kennedy assassination.
What about that thing?
We don't know what
that thing is Sir.
Actually we really don't
know what any of them are.
Yes, yes we do.
They're mutants.
He has the power to control
metal last I checked.
That's what most of your
weapons were made of.
And she can
transform into anyone.
A general, a secret service
man, even you Mr. President.
She could walk into this office and order
a nuclear strike if she was in the mood.
And that's only two of them.
Well, do we have any
countermeasures, any defense?
I was waiting for you
to ask me that question.
That's an experimental
program, strictly off the books.
You're telling me these
mutants are out in the world
and our best defense are
these giant metal robots.
Many of the mutants
looks like us
my sentinels can
tell the difference.
I have 8 prototypes ready
to go, they're built out of
a space age polymer, not
an ounce of metal on them.
I wanna make a demonstration, I want the
world to know that we can protect them.
What do you need to get
these things operational.
I already gave that
number to congress.
Unfortunately they
elected to shut me down.
It's going to cost a
bit more to turn them on.
Whatever you need.
Oh and one more thing, if we
do manage to capture them.
I would like her for
research purposes of course.
How terrible?
What?
I mean, to be like that?
Like that?
Can you imagine?
How can she even look in the mirror?
Yes, I can.
From where did she come from?
You think she has any family?
Yes, she does..
If I see so much as a screw
I'll jam this into your throat.
How did you find me?
You taught me well.
It's been a long time
since we were this close.
I missed you.
You tried to kill me.
So the rest of us could live.
What do you mean?
I received a message
from the future.
Don't lie to me.
I never lied and I never will.
Humans use your blood, your genes to
create a weapon that wipes us all out.
I was only doing what I thought
necessary to secure our future.
So what's to stop me from killing
you right now and securing my future.
Nothing.
It doesn't matter anymore,
they have your DNA.
Your blood was on the street.
Whose fault was that?
Mine.
I've seen their plans.
They're creating a weapon and now they
have what they need to take it further.
We have to strike now while
we still hold the upper hand.
I've seen too many
friends die Eric.
I don't want a war.
I only want the man
who murdered them.
This is war.
What happened to you?
Did you lose your
way when I was gone?
Are you still Charles' Raven?
Or are you Mystique.
Trask is the enemy.
Killing one man isn't enough.
It never was for you.
Goodbye Eric.
What happened?
- Can he walk?
- He need his treatment.
Hank, I can hear them.
It's ok, I'll make it stop.
I'll get it.
Hey, hey, pull yourself
together it's not over yet.
You don't believe that.
How do you know?
As these go,
this comes back.
They all come back.
Look.
I'm still here.
She's still out there.
But we need your help Charles.
Not like this, I'll need "you".
We can't find Raven
not without your powers.
I added a little extra
cause you missed a dose.
Charles.
Hank! do me a favor.
Would you help me
to my study please?
Are you sure about this?
Absolutely not.
This creature is extraordinary.
Her genes could hold the
key to mutation itself.
I need more.
That's all they were able to
scrape off the pavement in Paris.
More than blood.
I need brain tissue,
spinal fluid, bone marrow.
Imagine sentinels that could
transform, adapt to any target.
If I could just
get my hands on her.
This girl,
she could lead the program forward
years, decades into the future.
How old is your son now, Major?
Jason?
He's coming up on 10 now
if you can believe it.
8 years from fighting age.
And how many of our sons and brothers
did we just ship home in body bags?
Maybe 50/55 thousands.
And how many more
on the other side?
Never before in all of
human history has there.
Been a cause which could
unite us as a species.
Until now.
You really hate mutants
doctor, don't you?
On the contrary.
I rather admire them.
The things they can do.
I see mutants as our salvation.
A common enemy.
A common struggle against
the ultimate enemy.
Extinction.
I believe our new friends are going
to help us Usher in a new era, Bill.
A new era of genuine
and long lasting peace.
Attention, Attention.
Transport departure
begins in an hour.
Repeat, transport
departure begins in an hour.
When was the last time
you were down here?
The last time we went looking
for students a lifetime ago.
Welcome Professor!
Raven is wounded,
she won't be moving fast.
These are muscles I haven't
stretched in a long time.
God.
Charles.
Charles, it's alright.
I'll go check the generator.
It's not the machinery is it?
I can't do this, my mind..
Yes you can.
It won't take it.
You're just a little rusty.
You don't understand, it's
not a question of being rusty.
I can flip the switches,
I can turn the knobs
but my power comes from here,
it comes from
and it's broken.
I feel like one of my students.
Helpless!
It was a mistake coming down here,
it was a mistake bringing Eric.
This whole thing has
been one bloody mistake.
I'm sorry Logan, but they
sent back the wrong man.
You're right.
I am.
Actually it was
supposed to be you
but I was the only one who
could physically make the trip.
And uh, I don't know
how long we've got here,
but I do know that a long time
a, actually, a long time from now.
I was your lost helpless student
and you unlocked my mind.
You showed me what I was,
you showed me what I could be.
I don't know how
to do that for you.
You're right, I don't.
But I know someone who might.
Look into my mind.
You saw what I did to Cerebro.
You don't want me
inside your head.
There's no damage you can do that
hasn't already been done, trust me.
Hi.
Hey Logan.
Hi... Jean.
Kill me.
I love you.
Why you poor...
poor man?
Look past me.
No I don't want your suffering
I don't want your future.
Look past my future.
Look for your future.
That's it.
Charles.
So this is what becomes of us.
Eric was right.
Humanity does this to us.
Not if we show
them a better path.
You still believe.
Just because someone stumbles, loses their
way, it doesn't mean they're lost forever.
Sometimes we all
need a little help.
I'm not the man I was.
I open my mind.
It almost overwhelms me.
You're afraid
and Cerebro knows it.
All those voices.
So much
pain.
It's not their pain
you're afraid of.
It's yours, Charles.
And as frightening as it may be.
Their pain will
make you stronger.
If you allow yourself to feel it,
embrace it.
It will make you more powerful
than you ever imagined.
It's the greatest gift we have.
To bear their pain
without breaking
and it's born from
the most human power.
Hope.
Please.
Charles,
we need you to hope again.
Find what you were looking for.
Power's back on.
Yes.
Yes it is.
She's lost too much blood.
She can't keep going like this.
We have no choice Bobby.
We can wake him up.
No.
They need more time.
I had a glimpse into the past.
If we wake Logan now we may
set off an even darker course.
They need more time.
Raven, stop.
Stop running.
Charles.
Where are you?
Back at the house
where you should be.
I need you to come home.
I know what I need to do.
If you kill Trask you'll be creating
countless more just like him.
Then I'll kill them too.
Those are Eric's words,
not yours.
The girl I grew up with
wasn't capable of killing.
She was good, fair,
full of compassion.
I have compassion.
Just not for Trask.
He's been murdering
too many of us.
Shut her down Charles,
get in her head.
She's not letting me in.
I'm barely holding on,
I'm not strong enough yet.
I know what Trask has done.
But killing him will
not bring them back.
It will set you on a path
from which there is no return.
An endless cycle of killing.
Us and them till
there is nothing left.
But we can stop it
right now you and I.
You just "have" to come home.
I "have" to.
You haven't changed
at all Charles.
Like I said, I know
exactly what I have to do.
Where is she?
At an airport boarding a plane.
A plane to where?
Washington DC.
Hey guys.
There's something
I need to show you.
We're going backwards in time.
This the system I
designed to record any
news about Paris over
all 3 networks and PBS.
All 3? Wow.
Yeah... and PBS.
Look what I found.
Tomorrow in front of the white house
the President will make his announcement.
He'll be joined by secretary
of defense Laird and has
even sought the help of renowned
scientist Bolivar Trask
his special advisor to
combat this mutant issue.
Raven doesn't realize but
if she kills Trask at
an event like that with
the whole world watching.
Then I came a long
way for nothing.
And there's more bad news,
I saw a report
they found traces of
her blood in Paris.
For all we know they
already have her DNA.
That's all they need to create
the sentinels in the future.
Now there's a theory in time
physics that time is immutable.
It's like a river, you can
throw a pebble and it will
create a ripple but the current
always corrects itself.
No matter what you do the river just
keeps flowing in the same direction.
What are you trying to say?
I'm saying that,
what if the war is inevitable?
What if she's
meant to kill Trask?
What if this is just
simply who she is?
Just because someone stumbles,
loses their way
doesn't mean
they're lost forever?
No I don't believe
that theory Hank
and I cannot believe
that that is who she is.
Ready the plane
we're going to Washington.
You alright
getting there.
Whatever happens today I need
you to promise me something.
You looked into my mind and you've seen
a lot of bad but you've seen the good too.
The X-Men.
Promise me you'll find us.
Use your power,
bring us together.
Guide us, lead us.
Storm, Scott, Jean
remember those names.
There's so many of us.
We will need you Professor.
I'll do my best.
Your best is enough.
Trust me.
12 carriers inbound.
10 Miles.
They found us.
Thousands of people will be
gathered here today they've
come from all over the
world to witness history
along with news crews from at
least 50 different countries.
Can I see your
invitations please?
Yes you may.
These two are with me.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
Logan.
Please, this way Sir.
Haven't found her yet
but she has to be here.
The President of
the United States.
My fellow Americans.
Today we face the greatest
threat in our history.
Mutants.
We have prepared for this threat.
In the immortal words
of Robert Oppenheimer.
Behold.
The world will never
be the same again.
Can I help you?
No you can't.
Here they come.
This for you
brothers and sisters.
Raven.
I have her.
Let me go Charles.
There, you see?
Secret service man
left of the stage.
Got it. Go.
What the hell are you doing? I
didn't tell you to activate them.
I didn't..
Raven please listen to me.
We've been given a second
chance to define who we are.
Don't do this.
Gentlemen,
you cannot pass this point.
We can't stop that many.
No, but we can slow them down.
What the hell is happening?
Eric.
Storm.
Take us to Def con 3.
Mr. President we are code red.
What the hell happened out there?
I will fix it.
You said that before.
I wanted to make a statement.
Now the whole goddamn world
knows we can't protect them.
I will fix it.
You damn well better.
Charles.
Is everybody ok?
Storm.
Behind you.
Now.
Go.
I'm probably not supposed
to ask this kinda thing,
but in the future
do I make it?
No.
But we can change it, right?
Do what you were made for.
Where are you?
I got this.
Go.
Oh dear God, no.
So much for being a survivor.
One of them is in here.
Gun.
No no no no, don't kill it.
I need it alive.
What the hell has happened?
You built these
weapons to destroy us.
Why?
Because you're
afraid of our gifts.
Because we are different.
Humanity has always feared
that which is different.
Well I'm here to tell you...
to tell the world...
you're right to fear us.
We are the future.
We are the ones who
will inherit this earth
and anyone who stands
in our way will suffer...
the same fate as these
men you see before you.
Today was meant to be
a display of your power...
instead I give you a glimpse of the
devastation my race can unleash upon yours.
Let this be a
warning to the world...
and to my mutant brothers
and sisters out there.
I say this...
no more hiding,
no more suffering.
You have lived in the shadows
and shame and fear for too long.
Come out.
Join me.
Fight together in the
brotherhood of our kind.
A new tomorrow.
That starts today.
All those years wasted
fighting each other Charles.
To have a precious
few of them back.
- Mr. President, no.
- Stand down.
I said stand down.
You wanna make a statement.
Kill me fine but
spare everyone else.
Very heroic, Mr. President.
But you have no intention
of sparing any of us.
The future of our
species begins now.
You used to be a better shot.
Trust me, I still am.
Get out of my head Charles.
Raven.
Please,
do not make us the enemy today.
Look around you, we already are.
Not all of us.
All you've done so far is
save the lives of these men.
You can show them a better path.
Shut her down Charles.
I've been trying to control
you ever since the day we met.
And look what that's got us?
Everything that happens now
is in your hands.
I have faith in you, Raven.
He's all yours, Charles.
If you let them have me
I'm as good as dead.
You know that.
I know.
Goodbye old friend.
Goodbye Eric.
You sure you should let them go.
Yes.
I have hope for them.
There's going to be a time, Hank.
When we're all together.
What about Logan?
Good morning Logan.
Late start.
Good job thank you.
Very good job.
Storm.
Jean.
Hey Logan.
Are you okay?
You're here.
Where else would I be?
Whoa!
Easy pal.
Some things never change.
Good to see you Scott.
Uh huh.
Take it easy ok.
Professor.
Logan.
Is everything alright?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think it is.
You did it.
Did what?
Logan, don't you
have a class to teach?
A class to.. Teach?
Yeah, history.
History?
Actually I could use
some help with that.
Help with what?
Pretty much
everything after 1973.
The history I know
is a little different.
Welcome back.
It's good to see you Charles.
It's good to see everyone.
Well.
I had a promise to keep.
You and I have a lot
of catching up to do.
Yeah.
What's the last
thing you remember?
Drowning.
The past.
A new and unsettled world.
A world with endless
possibilities.
And infinite outcomes.
Isn't he?
Oh he's alive.
Countless choices
define our faith.
Each choice.
Each moment.
A ripple in the river of time.
What do you want us to do
with him, Major Stryker?
Enough ripples and
you change the tide.
I'll take him from here.
For the future is
never truly set.